Guide to the Ronald Lawson Research Files for the Tenant Movement in New York City TAM.214
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Ronald Lawson Research Files for the Tenant Movement in New York City
Circa 1960s-1980s
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Lawson, Ronald, 1940-
TAM.214
20 Linear Feet (20 boxes)
Ronald Lawson (1940-) is a professor emeritus of the Urban Studies Department at Queens College, the City University of New York, and the editor of and contributing author to The Tenant Movement in New York City, 1904-1984 (1986), for which he attended meetings of various tenant organizations. The collection contains detailed accounts of building conditions, rent strikes, lobbying and other activism. There are files on tenant organizations from the individual building level to the New York City and New York State level, which include meeting minutes, correspondence, internal documents and public statements and printed ephemera; several boxes of questionnaires filled out by local movement activists and leaders, and, scattered thoughout the collection, numerous interviews with such individuals. There is a smaller amount of like materials created by landlords and their organizations. There are also several book-length "manuscripts" by Lawson (i.e., a combination of narrative, notes, interviews and other materials), on organizations such as the Metropolitan Council on Housing, the Bay Ridge (Brooklyn) organization of the Metropolitan Council on Housing, the New York State Tenants' Legislative Coalition, the Brooklyn Tenants Union, the Riverside Edgecombe Neighborhood Association, and others. There are also papers by Lawson's college students, some of them case studies of living conditions in individual buildings and/or of tenant organizations therein.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Ronald Lawson in 1999. The accession number associated with this collection is 1999.019.
Arrangement
Arranged topically.
Historical/Biographical Note
Ronald Lawson (1940-) is a professor emeritus of the Urban Studies Department at Queens College, the City University of New York, and the editor of and contributing author to The Tenant Movement in New York City, 1904-1984 (1986), for which he attended meetings of various tenant organizations.
Scope and Contents
The collection contains Lawson's research files for his book on tenant movements in the New York Metropolitan Area. These files contain detailed accounts of building conditions, rent strikes, lobbying and other activism. This collection includes files on tenant organizations from the individual building level to the New York City and New York State level, which include meeting minutes, correspondence, internal documents and public statements and printed ephemera. There are several boxes of questionnaires filled out by local movement activists and leaders, and, scattered thoughout the collection, numerous interviews with such individuals. There is a smaller amount of like materials created by landlords and their organizations. There are also several book-length "manuscripts" by Lawson (i.e., a combination of narrative, notes, interviews and other materials), on organizations such as the Metropolitan Council on Housing, the Bay Ridge (Brooklyn) organization of the Metropolitan Council on Housing, the New York State Tenants' Legislative Coalition, the Brooklyn Tenants Union, the Riverside Edgecombe Neighborhood Association, and others. There are also papers by Lawson's college students, some of them case studies of living conditions in individual buildings and/or of tenant organizations therein.
Landlord and tenant -- New York (State) -- New York; Landlord and tenant |z New York (State); Tenants' associations -- New York (State) -- New York.; Tenants' associations |z New York (State); Research (document genres).; Term papers.; Manuscripts; Reports.; Manhattan (New York, N.Y.) |x Social conditions.; Interviews.; Manuscripts for publication.; Research notes.; Bay Ridge (New York, N.Y.) |x Social conditions.; Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Social conditions.; Queens (New York, N.Y.) |x Social conditions.; New York (N.Y.) -- Buildings, structures, etc.; Housing policy -- New York (State); Housing policy -- New York (State) -- New York.; Questionnaires.; Rent strikes -- New York (State) -- New York; Rent control -- New York (State) -- New York; Housing -- New York (State) -- New York; Rent control |z New York (State); Housing |z New York (State); Metropolitan Council on Housing (New York, N.Y.); Lawson, Ronald, 1940-; Riverside Edgecombe Neighborhood Association (New York, N.Y.); Brooklyn Tenants Union; New York State Tenants' Legislative Coalition; Metropolitan Council on Housing (New York, N.Y.). Bay Ridge Branch
- Research Files (box 1): Includes Metropolitan Council on Housing; New York State Tenants' Legislative Coalition
  - Lenox Hill Association, Oct 1973-Apr 1974 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Pratt Coalition Conference, Jun 1975 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Rent Strikes: Case Studies of the Dynamics of Political Protest Thesis by Merrick T. Rossum, Jun 1973 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - "Housing and Tenants' Movements in United States Cities: 1930-1980" by Cindy Colter S.U.N.Y. Binghamton, Winter 1984 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Rudell, William B., "Concerted Rent-Withholding on the New York City Housing Front: Who Gets What, Why and How?" Yale Law School: Property Law Division., Spring 1965 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Met Council, 1975-Oct 6, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Met Council, Sep 1973 - Sep 13, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Met Council - 200, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Met Council - Oil and Leaders, Jan 9, 1973-Dec 24, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Met Council Meeting Notes, Sep 12, 1973-Feb 23, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Met Council - 400, Jan 9, 1973-1974 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Met Council - 300, Sep 21, 1973, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Met Council - 100, undated, Sep 21, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Met Council - 500, undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Met Council - 600, undated, 1793 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Met Council - 700, undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Met Council - 800, Sep 12, 1973; undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Met Council - 900, Sep 12, 1973-Jan 26, 1974, undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - New York State Tenants' Legislative Coalition, Feb 5, 1974-May 7, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - New York State Tenants' Legislative Coalition, Apr 18, 1974-Jan 16, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - New York State Tenants' Legislative Coalition - 100 (Meeting Notes, Interviews and Manuscript), Feb 5, 1974-Apr 1974 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - New York State Tenants' Legislative Coalition - 100, Sep 20, 1973-Feb 1974, undated (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - New York State Tenants' Legislative Coalition - 100, undated (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - New York State Tenants' Legislative Coalition - 100, Dec 14, 1973-May 16, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - New York State Tenants' Legislative Council - 200, undated (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - New York State Tenants' Legislative Council - 300, Apr 4, 1974-Apr 23, 1974, undated (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - New York State Tenants' Legislative Council - 400, Jan 23, 1974-May 16, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - New York Tenants' Legislative Coalition, Jan 9, 1974-Feb 24, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - New York Tenants' Legislative Coalition, May 25, 1973-Sep 11, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - New York State Tenants' Legislative Coalition - 600, Mar 26, 1974, undated (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - New York State Tenants' Legislative Coalition - 700, Mar 16, 1974-Mar 19, 1974, undated (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - New York State Tenants' Legislative Coalition - 800, Dec 14, 1973-May 17, 1974, undated (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - New York State Tenants' Legislative Coalition - 900, Feb 20, 1974-May 16, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - New York State Tenants' Legislative Coalition - Extra Sheets, Dec 14, 1973- May 7, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - People's Housing Network, Aug 23, 1976, undated (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - New York State Tenant and Neighborhood Coalition, Jul 25, 1976-Sep 26, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - New York State Tenants Legislative Coalition; New York State Tenant and Neighborhood Coalition (resolutions and memoranda), Mar 19, 1974-Aug 15, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 37)
- Research Files (box 2): Includes Brooklyn Tenants Union; Bay Ridge Metropolitan Council on Housing.
  - Fresh Meadows Tenants Association, Nov 26, 1973-Feb 1977 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Fresh Meadows - Monograph by S. Burgharto, undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Steve Burghart - original monograph, undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Project Monograph: Hillside Tenant Union, undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Andrewin, Michelle Arlette. "The Columbia Tenants Union, A Success Story in a Transition Area.", undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Columbia Tenants Union, 1973-1975 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Columbia Tenants Union: 004 and Leaders, Fall 1973 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Coop City, Student Papers, T.A., Bldg 28, Fall 1973; May 15, 1974-May 17, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Coop City Clippings, 1975-1976 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Coop City, Class Papers, undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Coop City - Student Papers, May 10, 1974-Feb 1976, undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Coop City (Rent Strike), Jan 6, 1975-Jan 14, 1975, undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Brooklyn Tenants Union, Oct 1, 1973-Feb 1974; undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Kennedy, Steven S. "Tenant Organizing in a Working Class Context: A Case Study of 150 Crown Street and Other Building s of Brooklyn Tenants Union in Crown Heights, Brooklyn.", May 24, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Brooklyn Tenants Union, 1973-Feb 6, 1975, undated (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Brooklyn Tenants Union - Student Papers, Fall 1975-Fall 1976, undated (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Brooklyn Tenants Union - Meeting Notes, Sep 20, 1973-Feb 13, 1974, undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Brooklyn Tenants Union, Sep 20, 1973-Apr 17, 1974, undated (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Brooklyn Tenants Union - 023 and Leaders, Oct 17, 1973-Apr 17, 1974, undated (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Brooklyn Tenants Union - 100: Ecology, Oct 17, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Brooklyn Tenants Union - 200: Beginnings and History, undated (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Brooklyn Tenants Union - 300: Structure and Finances, Oct 17, 1973-Nov 8, 1973, undated (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Brooklyn Tenants Union - 400: Goals and Tactics, Sep 26, 1973-Feb 13, 1974, undated (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Brooklyn Tenants Union - 500: Leaders and Key Personnel, Oct 17, 1973-Apr 17, 1974, undated (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Brooklyn Tenants Union - 600: Membership, Mobilization, Sep 26, 1973-Feb 13, 1974, undated (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Brooklyn Tenants Union - 700: Observer and the Group, Oct 2, 1973-Jan 1974, undated (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Brooklyn Tenants Union - 800: Movement, Key Issues, Sep 20, 1973, undated (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Brooklyn Tenants Union - 900: Related Institutions, Oct 9, 1973-Nov 8, 1973, undated (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Bay Ridge (MCH), Nov 23, 1973-Feb 5, 1974, undated (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Bay Ridge (MCH) - Student Papers, Apr 20, 1972-Jan 3, 1973, undated (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Bay Ridge (MCH) Meeting Notes, Nov 1, 1973-May 16, 1974, undated (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Bay Ridge (MCH) Meeting Notes, Nov 1, 1973-May 16, 1974, undated (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Bay Ridge (MCH) - 020 and Leaders, Mar 2, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Bay Ridge (MCH) - 100, Nov 1, 1973-Feb 7, 1974, undated (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Bay Ridge (MCH) - 200, Feb 28, 1974, May 16, 1974, undated (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Bay Ridge (MCH) - 300, Nov 1, 1973-Feb 1974, undated (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Bay Ridge (MCH) - 400, Dec 13, 1973-May 16, 1974, undated (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Bay Ridge (MCH) - 500, Jan 1974-May 16, 1974, undated (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Bay Ridge (MCH) - 600, Nov 1, 1973-May 16,1973, undated (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Bay Ridge (MCH) - 700, Dec 1973-Feb 1974 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Bay Ridge (MCH) - 800, Feb 1974-May 16, 1974, undated (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Bay Ridge (MCH) - 900, Jan 24, 1974-May 16, 1974, undated (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Bay Ridge (MCH) - Additional Materials, Nov 1, 1973-May 16, 1974, undated (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - West Side Branch (MCH), Oct 28, 1976, undated (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - East Side Branch (MCH) - Student Papers, Spring 1974, undated (Box 2, Folder 45)
- Research Files (box 3): Includes Single Building Groups; Student Papers.
  - Interviews, Jan 1976-Apr 1976 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Clippings (Copies), Aug 1947-Mar 1949 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - "Sex Roles in Social Movements: A Case Study of the Tenant Movement in New York City", undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - The Worker. (Communist Party U.S.A. Newspaper. Articles: Typed Copies, Summaries, or Headlines), 1960-1966 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Metropolitan Council on Housing: 6th Annual Conference: Organize Tenants for an Open City "Bust the Ghetto", Nov 14, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Participant Observation of Tenant Meetings, Sep 21, 1973-Jun 15, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - St. Georges, Philip. They Shall Rebuild the Ruined Cities: Urban Homesteading and Sweat Equity in New York City. (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Interfaith Adopt-a-Building, Inc. "Sweat Equity Financing: A Case Study Prepared for the Office of Neighborhood Development Department of Housing and Urban Development", Feb 1979 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Single Building Groups: Meeting Notes, Jun 25, 1974-Aug 19, 1974, undated (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Single Building Groups, Jun 24, 1974-Jun 30, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Single Building Groups: 048 and Leaders (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Single Building Groups: Extra Sheets, Jun 23, 1974-Jun 30, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Single Building Groups: 700, Jun 23, 1974-Jun 30, 1974, undated (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Single Unorganized Buildings - Student Papers, Jan 2, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - 806 Suburban Place - Student Papers, Nov 12, 1973; Jan 2, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Tenant Organizations - Student Papers, Includes Some Case Studies, 1975-1976 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Rent Strikes - Student Papers, May 27, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Class Assignments and Student Papers, Apr 1975, May 1975, undated (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Tenant Organization 32 - Student Papers, Jan 2, 1974, undated (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Student Papers: Fieldwork Reports, Surveys, Interviews, May 29, 1974 - Aug 31, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Student Building Interviews, Mar 1975-May 1975; undated (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Krasner, Michael. "Democracy and Power in a Community Organization: The Adams Morgan Organization", undated (Box 3, Folder 22)
- Research Files (box 4): Includes Riverside Edgecombe Neighborhood Association
  - Riverside Edgecombe Neighborhood Association (RENA), Coalition of Riverside Tenants Association (CORTA), NAC 5: Student Papers and Field placement; "A Place to Live: A Study of Two Tenant Organizations", Feb 1972, Fall 1975, undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - R.E.N.A. - "Jubilee Year of the Good Neighbor", 1970 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - R.E.N.A.: 029 and Leaders, undated (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - R.E.N.A. - Student Papers, Jan 2, 1973, Fall 1976, undated (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - R.E.N.A. W.H.T.A. Field Notes, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - R.E.N.A. - Student Papers, Fall 1974, undated (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Building Studies - Research Guide, undated (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - "At the Threshhold of Organizing - Selecting Where to Become Involved", undated (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Tenant Organizing, Nov 1966-Jan 1976, undated (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Tenant Organization - Case Studies, undated (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - East Side Tenant Union - Case Studies, undated (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Fresh Meadows Tenant Association, undated (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - East 50's Association, undated (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Columbia Tenants Union, undated (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Women in Tenant Organizing, undated (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - [Tenant Organizing] - "Basic Research Methods" course - Student Papers, Aug 17, 1976-Jun 19, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Landlord Responses to Tenant Organizations, undated (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Hawley, Peter K. "Housing in the Public Domain: The Only Solution." Metropolitan Council on Housing., 1976 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - American Property Rights Association: Landlord Organization - Student Report, undated (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Susan's Working Papers for Building Level Study, Jun 23, 197x (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Susan's Working Papers for Building Level Study, Jun 23, 197x (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Landlords - Interviews, c. 1970s (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Met Council: Minutes of Executive Meetings, c. 1970s (Box 4, Folder 23)
- Research Files (box 5): Includes Building Organization Follow-Up Questionnaire
  - 8 inch box of tenant organization 6 inch by 4 inch index cards, undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - 1974 Lobbiests - Questionnaire mailed on June 26th, N=61, Ed Cohanski, Marie Ranyon, Dave Buchwalter, Jean Rippel, Dave Ross, Rick Braun, Steve Grathwohl, c. June 26, 1974, undated (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Politics, May 23, 1977 - Aug 30, 1977, undated (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Bronx Realty Advisory Board, Jan 20, 1974-Spr 1981, undated (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Landlord Groups 900's, Dec 26, 1973-Feb 7, 1974, undated (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Council of Property Owners' Associations, Apr 29, 1974, undated (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Community Housing Improvement Program, Nov 27, 1973-Apr 1974 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Politics, Mar 10, 1975-Jun 18, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Effectiveness, Jan 5, 1977-Dec 1, 1980, undated (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Tenant Movement Study: Building Organization Follow-Up Questionnaire, Fall 1980 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Tenant Movement Study: Building Organization Follow-Up Questionnaire, Fall 1980 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Tenant Movement Study: Building Organization Follow-Up Questionnaire, Fall 1980 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Tenant Movement Study: Building Organization Follow-Up Questionnaire, Fall 1980 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Tenant Movement Study: Building Organization Follow-Up Questionnaire, Fall 1980 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Tenant Movement Study: Building Organization Follow-Up Questionnaire Summary, Fall 1980 (Box 5, Folder 15)
- Research Files (box 6): Leadership Questionnaires: Neighborhood Organizations
  - Action for Progess: Ms. Merced (001-01), undated (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Action for Progress: Norman Miranda (001-02), undated (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Adopt-A-Building: Ruth Garcia (002-01), undated (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Adopt-A-Building: Rabbit Nazario (002-02), undated (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Adopt-A-Building: Sister Susan Treanor (002-03), undated (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Advisory Council for Tenants: Florette Marks (003-01), undated (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Association of Neighborhood Housing Developers: Robert Schur (004-01), undated (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Association of Neighborhood Housing Developers: Judy Flynn (004-05), undated (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Association of Neighborhood Housing Developers: Kathy Sanders (004-02), undated (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Association of Neighborhood Housing Developers: Henry Lanier (004-03), undated (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Association of Neighborhood Housing Developers: Roberto Nazario (004-04), undated (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Bathgate Community Development: Sonia Valdes (005-01), undated (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Bathgate Community Development: Robert Rodino (005-02), undated (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Bedford-Stuyvesant Restoration Corporation: Delores Silvey (006-03), undated (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Bedford-Stuyvesant Restoration Corporation: Albert Edwards (006-02), undated (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Bedford-Stuyvesant Restoration Corporation: Walter Chin (006-01), undated (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Bedford-Stuyvesant Tenant Action Committee: Rev. Patrick Kane (007-01), undated (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Bensonhurst Tenants Council: F. Barbaro (008-01), undated (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Bensonhurst Tenants Council: Hazel Mushynsky (008-02), undated (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Boro Park Tenants Council: Hedda Mazda (009-01), undated (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Boro Park Tenants Council: Mildred Lee (009-02), undated (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Boro Park Tenants Council: Ms. Taffler (009-03), undated (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Brighton Beach Tenants Council: Dan Hoober (010-01), undated (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Brooklyn Tenants Union: Mike McKee (011-01), undated (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Brooklyn Tenants Union: Dorothy Guet (011-02), undated (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Broome Street Tenant Association: Mrs. Riviera (012-01), undated (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Bronx League Against Slum Tenancies: Father Donahue (013-01), undated (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Brownsville Community Corp.: William Kelsey (014-01), undated (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Brownsville Community Council Center 1: Mrs. Trannie Pringle (015-01) (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Brownsville Community Council Center 4: Mary Wallace (016-01), undated (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Carnegie Hill Neighbors: Fred Papert (017-01), undated (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Center for Tenants Rights: David Nloore (018-01), undated (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - Central Queens Community Corp.: Reverand King (019-01), undated (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - Central Queens Community Corp.: David Simpser (019-02), undated (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - Chelsea Action Center: Arnaldo Senara (020-01), undated (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - Chelsea Action Center: Mrs. Alvarado (020-02), undated (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - Chelsea Coalition on Housing: Jane Woods (021-01), undated (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - Chelsea Coalition on Housing: Susan Cohen (021-02), undated (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - Churches United for a Better East Side: Mrs. Pat McCullough (022-01), undated (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - Churches United for a Better Manhattan: Father Robert Richie (022-02), undated (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - Citizens Committee of Washington Heights: Ms. Becker (023-01), undated (Box 6, Folder 41)
  - Citizens Committee of Washington Heights: Edith Kamiat (023-02), undated (Box 6, Folder 42)
  - City-Wide Anti-Poverty Committee on Housing: Willis McCartney (024-01), undated (Box 6, Folder 43)
  - City-Wide Anti-Poverty Committee on Housing: Rev. R. McCoy (024-02), undated (Box 6, Folder 44)
  - City-Wide Save Our Homes: Vicky Spiegal (025-01), undated (Box 6, Folder 45)
  - Claremont Housing Services: Ms. Simmons (026-01), undated (Box 6, Folder 46)
  - Claremont Neighborhood Association: Mrs. Powell (026-02), undated (Box 6, Folder 47)
  - Coalition for Human Housing: Kay Crampson (027-01), undated (Box 6, Folder 48)
  - Coalition for Mitchell-Lama Developments: Mr. Abe Cohen (028-01), undated (Box 6, Folder 49)
  - Coalition for Mitchell-Lama Developments: Charles Mendelson (028-02), undated (Box 6, Folder 50)
  - Columbia Tenants Union: Bruce Bailey (029-01), undated (Box 6, Folder 51)
  - Community Action Inc.: Michael Terwilliger (030-01), undated (Box 6, Folder 52)
  - Coney Island Housing Program: Reverend R. Tucker (031-01), undated (Box 6, Folder 53)
  - Cooper Square Community Development: Pat Hardig (033-02), undated (Box 6, Folder 54)
  - Cooper Square Community Development and Businessmans Corporation: Lois Dodd (033-01), undated (Box 6, Folder 55)
  - Coalition of Riverside Tenants Association: Luana Robinson (034-01), undated (Box 6, Folder 56)
  - Council of Tenant Associations of the Malohn Buildings: Bruce Marcus (035-01), undated (Box 6, Folder 57)
  - Council of Tenant Associations of the Malohn Buildings: Ms. Kaufman (035-02), undated (Box 6, Folder 58)
  - Crotona Tenants Coalition: Mrs. Mitchell (036-01), undated (Box 6, Folder 59)
  - Dorchester Towers Tenants Council: Eugene Hide (037-01), undated (Box 6, Folder 60)
  - Dorchester Towers Tenants Council: Hans Reinisch (037-02), undated (Box 6, Folder 61)
  - East 49th Street Tenant Group: Shirley Ryan (038-01), undated (Box 6, Folder 62)
  - East Harlem Tenants Council: Ben Flores (040-01), undated (Box 6, Folder 63)
  - East Tremont Action Committee: Isabel Valentin (042-01), undated (Box 6, Folder 64)